Task number 22.
In this task the customer gives us
two values: a number and a factor.
This is the number of squares that they
want. And this is the scaling factor.
And depending on the number and the
factor, we produce something like this.
So, this here is the output when we
use a number 10 and a factor 0.3.
And as you can see, these squares are
translated by some value to the right.
The first square is translated by
2, which is the first prime number.
The second square is translated by 3, which
is the second prime number, and so on.
And how do we get the prime numbers?
Luckily for us, we have this function here.
This function gives us a list of all prime
numbers starting from 2, 3, 5, and so on.
And this list is infinite.
So, we can get as many prime
numbers from it as we need.
Also, we have assortedColors which
is an infinite list of colors.
So, now we have two infinite lists.
And now let's say the customer wants 10
squares, which means we get 10 elements from
each of these two lists.
And this is how we do it.
We say take 10, for example,
from the list assortedColors.
And we have to do the same for the
other infinite list, which is 'primes'.
Yes, it's called primes.
So, we say: take 10 times.
And now to avoid repetition.
And instead of using take on
the lists like this, we can use it on them at
once, and we can pair the first element from the
first list with the first element from the second
list, the second with the second, and so on.
And we do this by using the function “zip”.
So,
instead I'm going to do this:
“zip” assortedColors and primes.
Now what we have here is an infinite list. We
take exactly the number that the customer wants.
Now let's make a list of
squares based on these values.
So, we're going to use them in a list.
And we say we want solid rectangles.
And here in the task it says:
they have the size of five by
five. Five by five squares, okay.
And here we have a tuple.
Let's say it's c for color and x for
whatever… a prime number. That's a p.
And each rectangle or each square is translated
by p, which is the prime number, and 0 because
it's not going to… it's going to
be translated only horizontally.
And of course, we need to
color it with the color c.
Here we have it.
This here is number not numbers.
Now this list contains Pictures,
and we need to join them into one Picture using
this function. We still have a small problem here
which is p, because the function “translated”
expects Double, it doesn't expect Integer,
while p here is an Integer because it comes from
this list 'primes', which is a list of Integers.
To solve this problem, we do fromIntegral.
And now let's test and see what we have here.
It is kind of working. So, we are
getting squares which are translated by
prime values… prime numbers.
And this is okay.
But we still have two problems: the
first problem is the size of squares.
It's too big. We still
haven't used the factor yet.
And the second problem is the
order in which they appear.
So, we have the red square on top
here. But what we want is the blue one
is on top of the red one, the yellow one
is on top of the blue one, and so on.
So, first, I'm going to reverse the list,
and now let's test our code.
As you can see, it's already getting
better. Now, let's use the scaling factor.
Since everything here is just one Picture
in the end, because we have this function
“pictures”, so we can scale it all at
once by using the function dilated factor.
And we need brackets, of course, so that this
whole thing here gets considered as one parameter.
And now let's test.
As you can see, it's working if we
compare it to this one it's the same.
And now we have this part of the task where
we should write our function this way,
where g takes care of the general list
manipulations such as “take”, “zip”, “reverse”,
and f takes care of the rest which are
the things that have to do with Pictures
and functions from this library CodeWorld.
So, now we have two functions f
and g. And let's start with g.
So, g takes two lists and then applies
“zip” on them, and then “take” a
specific number, and then it “reverse”s them. So,
we have three parameters: one, two, and three.
Let's copy this here. Numbers
or number and x's and y's.
This one here would be y's. This one here
would be x's, and number is the same.
And now let's make f.
Let's copy this part.
If we look here, we see that
we need a list here and we need
a factor.
So, we need two parameters here:
list and factor.
We'll put the list here.
And we put the factor here.
Yeah, we have it already.
This should be done.
I believe that's it.
First, I'm going to swap these two
parameters to make it easier to read.
And then let's rewrite our
function using f and g.
I'm going to keep the original function
here as a comment just in case.
So, first we have g which takes a number and takes
two lists, which are, in our case, these two lists.
And of course, we have to
pay attention to the order.
So, first we have the list of colors
and then the list of prime numbers.
After applying this function g,
now what we have here is a list
which we can then use as a parameter in f.
So, I'm going to do this. I'm
going to say f factor brackets.
And that should be it.
Let's test our solution.
As you can see, it's working.
This means now we don't need this anymore.
But actually, I'm just going to keep it here,
so that we can look at it and compare.
We can see the original function here.
Yes, that was it.
No… actually, we are not done
yet. We should write the type
signatures for the functions. So,
f takes a factor which is Double,
and it takes a list… this list. And since
we know already that this list is going
to be a list of tuples of which the first element
is always going to be a color and the second.
element is going to be an
Integer, we can write this here.
And then, at the end it's
going to give us a Picture.
As you can see here, we have
this function “pictures”.
So, everything here inside these
brackets is going to be one Picture.
And then we're just going
to apply “dilated” on it.
So, it stays as a Picture. And now
let's write the type signature for g.
So, g takes a number which is an
Integer and it takes two lists.
And it applies these three functions
on them: “zip”, “take”, and “reverse”.
And we know that these three functions
do not care at all what type of list
they're dealing with, as long as they are lists.
So, this means we don't need to
specify. We just say: a list of type a,
and a list of type b. And then it gives us a
list of which every element is itself a tuple.
And the first one (element) is
going to be from this list.
So, it's going to be an a. The
second one is going to be a b.
There is still a problem here which is: it says:
couldn't match type Integer with Int. Expected
type is Color, Int, while we have Color,
Integer. So, we just change this here,
and it should work. Now, let's test our solution.
Okay, it's working.